[music]
>> There you go.
Oh, yeah, I got the door. How do you
want it to to end this season? Just your
thoughts on the game.
Yeah, um
I think
we just beat ourselves today.
False starts,
turnovers,
um
mental errors.
Certainly
wasn't
high-level football today.
Do you think that's
because it was the end of the season? Do
you think it's just sometimes a you have
those games the opponent makes sure
Um
it's tough to say. I mean,
we certainly can't have the mental
errors we had today.
Why What caused that? I don't know. I
don't know.
But,
can't happen.
You were able to keep Myles Garrett out
until we finally got the one late.
What was your approach to kind of
How big of a game part of the game plan
was keeping him
um
neutralized? How was that? Yeah, you
have you have to if you want to
be successful against that team.
He's the focus of our game plan every
time we play him. It's no secret. You
have to
and it it's challenging because you have
to
commit resources to that and that takes
away resources from from elsewhere.
But, for most part I thought we were
pretty good against them today, but you
can see how impactful he is. We have
no help on him one time and he gets one.
Um and then he was
>> [clears throat]
>> I'm pretty sure it was him that put his
put his hand up and and knocked the ball
down on the goal line into an
interception. I don't know that for sure
because I haven't watched the tape, but
uh it was it was his side. It was one of
those guys over there. Um so, he's an
aware
elite player that you have to
revolve your game plan around. We used
to ask you a lot about the future.
Sorry for a few future questions last
time we get to talk to you for a little
bit. How involved do you plan to be? I
know you said
quarterback, but you also know your
voice carries a lot of weight here in
this organization. How involved do you
plan to be in conversations with
Mike,
Duke, Zach immediately following the
season about what you think and what you
want this franchise to do to make sure
that this off-season goes the way that
you want it to. Yeah, I think
you know, we'll have those meetings the
next couple days. I think
um
I think for the most part we're on the
same page about what we have to do and
where we have to go.
Without having the meetings it's tough
to
to say, but
um
I know they certainly value my opinion.
I think
um
I think I think about things critically.
I think
that
I can provide some insight into
things going on
in the locker room and on the field that
>> [snorts]
>> could help us win and
so, I
plan to to voice some things just like I
do every off-season. Just to follow up
on that. I know you're not going to
share a lot publicly, but whatever
you're comfortable sharing if you had to
say what what you want to see most this
off-season done by this organization to
help support you, what would you say it
is?
>> [sighs]
>> Yeah, it's tough to say right now
without
talking to to people. And those meetings
will be done the next few days.
Uh I'm very confident in our coaching
staff. I know those guys work really
hard to to put us in good positions and
um
you know, I always feel
well prepared and
put in the best spot to go out and
succeed.
Um
so, from that standpoint I think
we're in a good spot. Do you have the
same level of confidence in the
organization as you did at the beginning
of the year or higher or lower? We all
want to win. We all want to win. Do you
think your
your championship mindset is being
matched organizationally? Do you see
that? Do you feel that? I mean, I sure
hope so. I think
um
I know everybody's frustrated right now.
So,
it's hard to There's a There's a
There's a disconnect during the season.
You know, we
we're all down here and focused on the
day-to-day and trying to get better and
um
it's their job upstairs to focus on the
big picture and where we need to go and
who we need to be. So,
um
I know they're committed to that. When
you guys were winning division titles
and going to the AFC Championship game
and went to Super Bowl 56,
a big reason why was some of your free
agents that you guys brought in and
external guys.
How important do you think that
is for this organization?
>> Yeah, that's that's that's that's of
paramount importance. I think
um
you have to
>> [snorts]
>> identify where
you're weak and figure out a way to be
strong in that area. That's that's the
NFL year in and year out. Um
sometimes it works out, sometimes it
doesn't, but
you have to attack that period with
intent to get better.
Were you surprised that
Garrett got the record? Zach said the
officials hadn't informed him in
advance. Yeah, I mean, was I surprised?
No.
Um
>> [snorts]
>> No, I I wasn't surprised. That's
typically how they handle those kinds of
situations. Can you walk us through that
play and that that led on the on his
sack what y'all called it and kind of
how he how he won? Do you remember?
>> [sighs]
>> You know, I'm trying I'm trying to
remember if we had
uh
It's tough to recall right now the the
exact protection
IDs on on that.
Whether we
cuz certain certain looks you can't
you can't have help on on 95 because of
the
potential pressure responses that they
give, but it's it's tough to
tough to remember the exact call on in
that situation off the top of my head.
When When going back to some of the
earlier questions, where you guys are
this far removed now from being in the
postseason, does that kind of wear on
you and build maybe a little bit more
pressure at you on everybody to get back
to that point when it gets further and
further away from where y'all expect to
be?
We We certainly aren't where
we want or need to be.
Not where I expect to be.
>> [clears throat and cough]
>> Um so,
yeah, we we we have to we have to figure
it out. We got to figure it out.
I don't I don't think you guys had a
catch in the second half until that last
drive anyway.
Did they do anything to open it up or
anything or
No.
Not not particularly. We want We wanted
to come in and run the ball.
Um
Try to mitigate the effect of their of
their rush and I think we [snorts] ran
it well.
We got to a point in the game that we
couldn't really do that anymore. So,
then we started dropping back and
throwing it a little more and
um
thought we were effective.
I don't think they I don't think they
did top corners
>> [cough]
>> very well really.
Did that Did you try to take advantage
of that or or was it kind of the day
went into something different? Yeah, I
think we we did take advantage of that
for the most part. I think we moved the
ball well all day.
Um
you know, it came down to to them making
a play on the goal line on the goal line
putting their hand up, getting a tip and
then
we fumbled and gave them another seven
points. Um
so, they without those two corners out
there they certainly called the game a
little differently than they would have
otherwise.
Uh
and
I also thought we
uh responded well to that and had the
answers to to to those coverages that we
were facing.
You talked about
needing to find a way to be on the field
more. When you reflected on the season,
was so many of your injuries just being
fluke? What do you mean by that and what
can you do if you can do anything? Yeah,
I don't I don't know. I don't know. I
don't I don't know if there's anything I
can do
about that.
Uh I work really hard to to be great at
this and try to put myself in a good
position
and put the team in a good position. So,
um
what whatever whatever that looks like
I'm not sure. I'm going to certainly
think critically about that and uh
maybe make some changes, maybe not.
Maybe I decide that what I'm doing is is
great and put myself in a good position
and you know, things happen. Uh but
certainly we'll think about it.
Physically, how are you feeling right
now? Yeah, I feel good. I feel good. Um
Yeah, I feel good. Mentally and
physically, how would you rate your
performances since you've been back and
do you feel like you are giving 100% all
the way?
Yeah, I'm really proud of what I did
this year. I'm really proud of what I
did this year. I
um came back from an injury faster than
any human ever has. I'm really proud of
that. I think I came back and played
some some really good football.
Uh
I had one bad game
and
you know, you certainly don't want any
of those, but I'm certainly not going to
lose my mind over that. I think
you know, when I came back, I I played
some really high-level football and
um
you know, I'm certainly proud of what I
did this year. Would you want to win
Comeback Player of the Year? I don't
know if you could win it after being out
in the same season.
>> Would I be eligible for it next year?
>> [laughter]
>> Maybe next year.
You look at where your career is six
years in, is it easier or more difficult
to block out the questions of what could
have been if, you know, you don't miss
so much time with injuries in those six
years?
Um yeah,
we're at where we're at. I'm at where
What's happened has happened.
Certainly don't want to miss as much
time as I have, but uh that's that's
where I'm at. So,
all you can do is
evaluate the position that you're in and
try to get better from there. Joe, Zach
was asked directly talked about kind of
the pursuit of happiness more than you
ever have. Why has that been such a big
theme for you over the course of the
season?
You know, I think if you want to play
this game for a long time, you got to
enjoy
what you do and who you do it with. And
you know, injuries certainly take a toll
on that.
And I just think in life
>> [snorts]
>> I certainly don't want to let
let let losing and where our
team is at at the moment
you know, affect all the other areas of
my life. Certainly not happy with
where we're at, but
you know, I'm not going to let that
affect who I am and and what I do and
how I think about things.
>> Is that Is that been a big shift I think
a lot of times a lot of people will say
it's been such a big part of your life
as it is. Have you been trying to maybe
separate how much happiness you get from
playing the game and how much it affects
the rest of you? Is that pretty fair to
say you think?
>> Yeah, I think so. I think so. I think
so. Um
you know, I work really hard at this. So
it certainly
a hard pill to swallow when
I'm getting injured the way that I am
and we're losing the way that we are.
And so
you know, I haven't gotten that joy out
of
this that I used to from
uh
you know, I
the joy that I got was winning. And uh
we certainly haven't haven't had that
success that we expect.
And so I'm not just going to sit around
and mope and
be miserable to be around from loved
ones and all of that. So
I think it's just growth and maturity.
Is there anything different you're going
to do maybe this off season as you get
prepared? Have you thought about that
part yet cuz we're
Um yes, I have thought about it, but not
not critically to the point of
change yet. Joe, Zach Is that What's the
next week like for you? Um
relax. Relax. Be around
friends and family and
stay up late.
Stay in bed late.
Uh
who knows right now. I'm not I'm
I got I got no no obligations for a
while. So
I'll just go to sleep when I get tired,
I guess. Who knows? Yeah, uh Zach was
asked about his message to the team
after the game and
the way you guys lost this game, he said
it was a little bit fitting. What are
your thoughts on that?
Yeah, it's certainly a microcosm of how
things have gone these last 2 years.
[clears throat]
We certainly expect to win that game and
we didn't make the plays to do it. And
you can say that for for a lot of for a
lot of games over the last 2 years.
Uh Joe, uh two part questions for me.
One, how did the offensive line grow
this year? And also with with having Joe
Flacco around, did you pick his brains?
Yeah, I think the O-line
had their best year since I've been
here. Uh
you know, I didn't get to experience
much of it
at the beginning of the year, but since
I've come back, I think it's the best
that they've been.
I think we've run it the best that we've
run it
since I've been here as well. And I
think that has opened up certain aspects
of our offense.
Um and I really enjoyed having Joe
in the room
getting to know him and you know,
sharing laughs and stories and and all
all of that. Uh we had a great
quarterback room this year, but
um you know, I I didn't get to
take as much part in it as I would have
liked, but you know, when I was in
there, I had a lot of fun.
When you guys come back from off season
workouts and Joe Flacco
is back in that room, would that that
make you happy? Yeah, I'd love that. I
think
number one, he played well when he was
in there.
And he's fun to watch. And
you know, he brings a a certain
perspective that
uh you don't [snorts] it's certainly
unique. You don't get to be around guys
that have played as long as he does and
has seen as much football
as he has.
And uh you know, I think he would be
valuable for us. I don't know if it
seemed like you got close a couple times
before he got that sack.
>> [clears throat]
>> Not just maybe not even just today, but
throughout the many times you face him,
how much does going up against him
really test that you know, that internal
clock more and as far as your reads and
everything you need to make sure that
you're
going to the right place that you know
where you need to be just in case cuz
you know, that's a guy that's just like
everybody said, he's just so much more
athletic than most guys out there.
>> Yeah, I I certainly don't go into a
a play thinking about it, but my my
natural instincts kick in and you feel
them quickly often.
And you know, that certainly affects
how far you can push the ball down the
field
the protections that you can call, the
plays that you can call and and how
quickly you want to get the ball out of
your hands.
You know, he's the best at what he does
and
>> [snorts]
>> you
try to make it mitigate that as much as
you can with
your play calls, your protection plan
and then how your quarterback plays. How
big are these next 8 months for for the
organization just to make sure that this
drought ends at three so that it doesn't
go to four so that you're competing for
the division again trying to get back to
the playoffs, back the AFC
[clears throat] title game, etc. etc. As
big as it gets.
Thanks, guys. Thanks, Joe. Thanks, Joe.